Mo' Better Blues is a drama, music film directed by Spike Lee.
Talented but self-centered trumpeter Bleek Gilliam is obsessed with his music
and indecisiveness about his girlfriends Indigo and Clarke.
But when he is forced to come to the aid of his manager and childhood
friend, Bleek finds his world more fragile than he ever imagined.
Bleek Gilliam, played by Denzel Washington.
Giant, played by Spike Lee.
Shadow Henderson (Sax), played by Wesley Snipes.
Left Hand Lacey (Piano), played by Giancarlo Esposito.
Butterbean Jones, played by Robin Harris.
Indigo, played by Joie Lee.
Mo' Better Blues is a 1990 American dramatic film starring Denzel Washington,
Wesley Snipes, and Spike Lee, who also wrote, produced, and directed.
It follows a period in the life of fictional jazz trumpeter Bleek Gilliam (played by Washington) as a series
of bad decisions result in his jeopardizing both his relationships and his playing career.
The film focuses on themes of friendship, loyalty, honesty,
cause-and-effect, and ultimately salvation.
It features the music of the Branford Marsalis
quartet and Terence Blanchard on trumpet.
The film was released five months after the death of Robin Harris and is
dedicated to his memory, being his final acting role.
The tone is emotional.